Some people call it vision. Vision is an
awfully big word to me because I I
believe first of all vision matters.
[music]
>> We preempted the weekly show. And
there's only three people we preempt the
show for. President Trump, Jesus, and
Jensen. [laughter]
>> The number one [music] podcast in the
world.
>> That's Jensen Wong.
>> He's the founder, president, CEO of
Nvidia.
>> Whether you know it or not, his
decisions are shaping your future.
>> Nvidia is the most important stock in
this market. Jensen is arguably the best
executive in history.
>> Revenue [music]
exploded 97% year-over-year.
>> Not only is demand already strong, is
actually accelerating. Nvidia is the
only computing platform that is a full
stack AI [music] factory. A GPU is like
a time machine because it lets you see
the future sooner. And if we could see
the future and we can predict the
future, then we have [music] a better
chance of making that future the best
version of it.
>> Please welcome Jensen Hang.
>> [music]
>> Oh, we got a standing O on the way in.
>> Oh, come on.
>> Standing O.
>> Standing O on the way in.
>> There's our guy. [laughter]
>> Ladies and gentlemen, GPU Jesus.
>> They love you.
>> Thank you. I love you back. Number one
podcast in the world.
>> In the world.
>> Absolutely.
>> Wow. We like the new jacket.
>> Well, you know, you auctioned the open.
>> I just I felt you guys needed some
energy.
>> Yes. This is the
>> I know we're talking about serious stuff
here, but we need to talk about it with
energy. Yes.
>> Let's uh let's start with this uh essay
from this weekend.
>> Which one? [laughter]
>> Let's start with Daario's essay because
>> was Hemingway involved? [laughter]
>> Actually, did anybody run it through
Pangram? I don't even know how much of
it was AI helped, but that was a pretty
incredible thing. And then I think what
a lot of people were surprised by was
the coalesing of the frontier labs
around the essay itself. Just Jensen
unpack what happened, how you read it,
how you interpreted it, and then we'll
get into some details that were inside
of it. But maybe just the highle
thoughts to kick it off.
>> Well, first of all, there were a lot of
stuff in there.
>> Yeah. and and uh uh first there is a
there's a part about about safety which
we have to take very seriously. Safety
is paramount. Obviously um uh safety and
leadership are not false. They're false
choices. You're you're able to innovate
quickly. You're able to execute quickly
and and uh America's able to lead and to
do it safely. I think those are those
are false choices but safety is
obviously important. Uh there's a matter
of of internal control that I think he
was speaking to. Uh obviously the the
coxin uh whistleblower is very serious
matter. When whenever you have a
whistleblower, you got to take it very
seriously. I thought Coxin
[clears throat] had great courage uh to
uh put out put out uh uh what his
concerns were. Um and even then there
were some issues that were kind of
conflated within that. Uh I think the
the the whistleblowing is is fine. I
think the the uh scientific prediction
uh about the future uh is less aligned
because it's not grounded on science
obviously and um uh it it was expressed
by a scientist but it was obviously not
grounded on science and and so I take I
take issue with that but obviously the
whistleblower part of it uh [snorts] you
know I I think there's just a whole
bunch of stuff uh pausing uh uh pacing
those are all the voluntary things that
they could do if they feel that their
company is out of control. Uh if Coxin
saw something, you know, obviously we
didn't we don't know what Coxin saw,
>> but he if he saw that the company was
out of control
>> and maybe it's a transition from uh uh
research to engineering. As you know,
these labs are research are
transitioning from research to
engineering. Extraordinary talent,
extraordinary engineering. Um but
obviously engineering is different than
research. Maybe that transition is
clumsy. you know, I don't we don't know
what what he saw and ultimately only he
knows. Um, but if there was a a matter
of lack of control, that's a different
topic. Um, how should the government
deal with it? Now all of a sudden, uh,
regulation and reg I mean it just covers
everything in one blog.
>> Can you just help us sort of unpack? We
we play we tried to play this game
actually this week on the pod and it was
difficult which is how do you describe
like you know my mom calls me and she's
like Jimoth what is this whole
civilizational death thing? I don't know
how to explain it to her. So when you
have very smart people like that
quantize it and quantify it, I think
that's probably what's perturbing to
some people. They're like, "What does
that mean, 10% of extinction?" Nobody
knows how to explain that to the average
person how that's even possible. Well,
first of all, we shouldn't
uh because it's made up. Uh first of all
I think that [laughter]
[applause]
we shouldn't because we it's made up and
these are these are well educated uh
they're called researchers um obviously
they're working in a lab and so the
confluence of these words and then and
then and then the prediction is alarming
and troubling and it shouldn't be done.
It's it's it's irresponsible. Now the
fact of the matter is let's go back and
look at the real facts. The facts are uh
there was a prediction that in 5 years
time radiology will be completely taken
over by artificial intelligence and
there'll be no radiologists in the
world. That has proven to be exactly the
opposite. We need more radiologists than
ever in the world. However, AI has taken
over radiology completely which is great
is automated scan reading which is
great. Um uh there was a prediction that
within 6 to 12 months, wasn't it just
last year? Within 6 to 12 months, uh 90%
of code would already be generated uh by
AI. That has turned out to be wrong. Uh
within 6 to9 months, that was predicted
last year, 50% of entry jobs will be
wiped out. That has proven to be wrong.
Uh let's see what else. What else has
proven to be wrong? I mean, all of these
predictions have been wrong,
>> right? Well, that GPT2 would be too
unsafe to release. That llama 3 would be
too unsafe to release.
>> Oh, one.
>> Yeah, we've heard the
>> half of white collar jobs would be gone
next year.
>> The jobs apocalypse. Yeah.
>> We have to take accountability. We have
to take account for all of the stupid
predictions that were made,
>> right?
>> Somebody has somebody has to take Yeah.
[applause]
>> And and so we ought to just keep track
of all that. And of course people do and
remind us that those those predictions
are inconsistent
with ultimately America winning the AI
race.
>> The short form for that is some people
are saying you know they say trust the
[clears throat] experts and they used
the analog of co which again started
with people that were researchers
educated people that had an asymmetric
awareness of the thing that the rest of
us did not saying things that ultimately
turned out we find out in facts uh not
to be true. Um, and so there's this war
that's happening right now between the
trust the experts movement and the, you
know, well, let's just look at the
actual history of these predictions and
let's just think more methodically.
Where is this coming from? Because it's
coming from inside the places that's
actually making it. Like what do you
think is the psychological makeup or
what is the real incentive? Maybe it's a
business incentive, maybe it's a
political incentive. Can you just maybe
guess or how do you how do you think
about what's why they're doing this?
Well, first of all, I got to tell you
these [clears throat] are some of the
most consequential companies in history.
Uh, uh, extraordinary engineers,
extraordinary researchers, uh, really
fantastic work. Um, [clears throat] uh,
on the one hand, uh, I work very closely
with them as companies to companies. Uh,
on the other hand, uh, we have to have
conversations like this in public. And
it's really unfortunate. And I I think
that that these these companies um
really ought to be built the way that we
used to build companies, which is in
silence,
>> right? You know, and
so wait, wait, Jensen, you don't allow
anybody in your organization to speak
for the entire organization, especially
when they're having like a bad weekend
or they rage quit. They're they're not
allowed to tweet on your behalf and the
organization's behalf. No, because well
that's that's what they decided when
they came to work for us and we told
them uh these are this is the way you
behave when you work in our company and
and uh if you would like if you like the
culture of our company um uh which as
you know the NVIDIA culture and the
NVIDIA employee base uh incredibly
happy. Yeah. uh they like the fact that
the company is consistent, that we're
stable, that our core values are
consistent with taking care of the
families and creating the conditions by
which they can do their life's work. Uh
that we do meaningful work, we do it we
do it as quietly as we can and uh we
contribute to everybody else's success,
which we're very proud of. And so those
kind of core values people are attracted
to. Um but when you come and work in our
company, there are also some things that
we don't appreciate that you do. Like
for example, we don't welcome uh
political discourse in our inside our
company. Take it home. You guys talk
about politics outside the company. Um
we
>> Yeah. [applause]
>> Uh we we are um the company is an
a-olitical company. You know, we're
bipartisan. We want America to succeed
and and um uh we want we want uh
whatever uh government is in place uh
we'll do everything in our power to help
America succeed. And so so the the
discourse about about uh about race and
religion and politics and all of that
stuff we tell people do it outside the
company. It's not not for us.
>> In terms of u maybe AI regulation then
more narrowly. Um Satya was here this
morning and what he said is you know
before we talk about regulation that
could really styy things why don't we
just get some basics right? Why don't we
get measurement right? Why don't we get
standardization right? Right. Um where
do you land on
>> get engineering right?
>> Get the engineering right. Right.
Translate the research in a more
predictable way so that we're not
fear-mongering. Keep it inside until
we're ready to expose it. Um what do you
think the right response is? You know
Demis had a proposal which was sort of
this more FINRA like organization. It's
not clear what Daria wants. This
transnational mutated thing that has
some sort of control. Where do you land
on this? The sort of perspective of what
what do we need right now?
>> You know, regulation should solve actual
problems.
And so the question is what actual
problems have we enjoyed,
>> right? And and um if you look at look at
the actual problems um all of the actual
problems so far have come from the labs.
And the reason for that, the reason for
that and and just in their defense, the
reason for that is because they have the
most compute,
>> right?
>> And the reason for that is because
they're trying to solve uh the frontier
problems. And so in their defense and so
it's sensible that that um the labs, the
frontier labs will be where the most
danger come from. It is unlikely that a
high school student uh did something
because they just simply won't have
enough compute,
>> right? And so uh it's unlikely that a
startup will be the reason because they
won't have enough compute. It's it's uh
they you know in fact you could look
across the planet and everybody won't
have enough compute with the exception
of the frontier labs. And so so now the
question is if you look at what actually
happened um and they're doing pioneering
work. It's really very hard. Um they're
transitioning from research to
engineering. Um, I could imagine and
they're they're they're they're
obviously building some of the most
consequential technology and companies
in the world. Uh, they're building their
company, they're building their culture,
they're building the technology, they're
building engineering, they're building
products all at the same time. And so I
I can understand it's a little bit hair
on fire. Um, uh, but nonetheless,
the four incidents from one lab, the one
giant incident from the other lab, um,
the first thing that you have to do is
just root cause the problem from an
engineering perspective. what happened,
>> what could we have done differently and
what are we going to in to implement and
institutionalize whether it's technology
or methods or processes and make sure
that we don't let it happen again. Now,
I would bet you money that in every
single one of those cases is within
their control
in the future to prevent it
because the alternative if it's not in
their control and I'm sure that they are
I'm sure I'm I'm sure that I'm sure
those four four incidents won't happen
again. Um they I'm sure they root caused
it and fixed it. I'm sure uh they have
now technology
for you know sandboxes and run times and
monitors and continuous in continuous
monitors and you know and so I'm I'm
certain they have much much better
technology now the alternative is also
unlikely which is for them to say look
we had these incidents after we're done
analyzing it we came to the conclusion
we don't know anything that happened and
we have no idea how to control it and
we're asking society for help.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, if that's the case, then we ought
to, you know, a bunch of bunch of
companies with engineers ought to send
engineers in. I mean, and we should
advise them if we can, but I doubt it. I
think they they have extraordinary
people. They got this handled.
>> But we we're not operating in a vacuum.
[clears throat] David, last night you
informed me that there is a Chinese lab,
the makers of GLM, who are going to put
three billion towards a recursive
self-improvement run. So, maybe you
could tee that up for J.
>> Well, that's what was announced. Yeah.
zpoo.com the founder just raised 5
billion and said that one of their
priorities is going to be trying to get
to recurs you know uh AI that trains the
next AI and to try and automate as much
of that as possible. Um yeah I think
that I mean
>> well this is the new sexy phrase but as
[snorts] you guys know RSI is a
combination of a system of ideas.
It's um it starts everything with in
context stuff. It starts with skills. It
starts with reflection. It starts with,
you know, reinforcement learning and
synthetic data generation. And these are
all very sensible ideas that causes AI
to get better at solving a problem, you
know, over time. And you could also have
uh low rank, you know, all of that stuff
doesn't include the weights. Uh you
could actually improve the weights and
it's called Laura. uh Laura could be
could be improved in synthet synthetic
data generation reinforcement learning
enhance it without training the the base
model itself and then over time uh you
could train the base model again with
all of that experience and and so I I
think I think it's a sensible thing that
that you're going to use the technology
uh to enhance productivity of all kinds
of tasks including building AI. I think
that's a very logical idea and and I'm
I'm certain that everybody is using it
in some degree. It's just this phrase is
now being used um to weaponize the
technology in some way and maybe to turn
the
>> as if it's going to spiral out of
control is the impression they're trying
to give. But you don't believe that's
real?
>> No. No, of course not. And the reason
for that is because you could RSI all
day long inside your company, but when
you release a product, you've got to
evaluate it, don't you? You have to test
it again, don't you? You have to make
sure that there's no regression, right?
And so the basic process of control.
These labs are going to as they move
from labs to engineering, they will have
much much better control,
>> right? And when they have much better
control that and control comes from
methods and knowledge and practice and
tools and technology all of those things
that leads to better control
verification and evals
>> it's going to enable RSI to be done
inside the company and for good products
to be released outside.
>> Let's talk about uh open source for a
second. I mean this hugging face we we
were communicating about this and I said
it's going to be one of the most
consequential
um
acquisitions. I don't even want to call
it a transaction because I think it's
more important than that. Um, give us
your first principles explanation of
open source versus closed source versus
open weights and how the ecosystem
should fit together over time.
>> The world needs both closed models and
open models. Um, you want you want to
use I use as much closed models as I
can. This weekend I I used four of them
and and [clears throat] uh they work
terrifically. They're frontier. They're
great experience. They right they work
incredibly well. They're getting better
all the time. Uh, and and the way I
think about closed closed closed models
is kind of like bottled water. You know,
water is free, you guys. I don't know if
I've told you guys, but water is free. I
I don't want to, you know, burst
everybody's bubble, but water's free.
And this morning, I used a lot of free
water taking a shower. And so, you use
the right water in the right places. And
this is no different than electricity.
This is, you know, this is no different
than all kinds of commodities that we
use in the world. You need both. Now in
the case of open the reason why that you
need it is because it could be for
sovereignty reasons, privacy reasons, um
proprietary technology reasons. Look at
the facts. The facts are in the last 6
months
$400 billion of venture funding went
into AI native companies.
>> 80% of them use open models. If not for
open models, how could they build their
dream,
>> right?
>> Because their dream could be different.
Obviously, it'll be different than the
labs, the frontier labs dreams. And
there's America has so many different
ways to innovate. That's one of our core
strengths. Great ideas just coming out
of the fountain. And and so open models
enables that. Open models enables every
single if we want to win the AI race.
It's not about a few technology
companies winning the AI race. It's
about every company in America. Every
comp, every company, every industry,
every researcher, every teacher, every
student, every startup, everybody wins.
Some of them will use closed models. A
lot of them will use open models.
There's 10 million
>> Does it matter?
>> Well, let me just ask, does it matter if
the model the open models come from
China or the US?
>> Well, we're doing everything we can um
to make a contribution in open models.
However, the moment you download, like
for example,
probably the vast majority of the
world's contribution to open source
today is coming from China. They just
have a lot more engineers. They produce
everything in large scale because it's a
larger country. And so they produce
science and math students in volume,
>> right?
>> That's one of our disadvantages, right?
>> They're manufacturing them through
amazing universities like Chinua
University in high volume. Well, they
contribute to open source today. We
download Linux. We download Kubernetes.
We download all the software. A lot of
it has been touched by Chinese. And once
you download it, it's yours. We fork it.
We improve it. We make it ours. And so
we when you download one of these
Chinese models, it just happens to be
made by some really great researchers in
China, but it's now yours. Whatever you
want to do with it.
>> So what exactly is the race?
the race.
>> Yeah,
>> I think that's that's a really good
point. My point is the race is really
about who exploits the technology best.
You know, the last industrial
revolution, all of the inventors were
Maxwell, Volulta, Ampier. None of them
were American.
They were right. The last industrial
revolution came from Europe. But we
exploited it. We took advantage of it
socially better than anybody else in the
world. Look how it turned out for us. I
want to make sure that this next
generation happens just like this.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So why why are the communists getting
their message out so successfully here
right now?
[laughter]
[clears throat]
>> You know I I think first of all the
narrative is much more practical.
The narrative is much more practical.
Nobody's in China is saying that there's
end of this and end of that and you know
cataclysmic this and you know
>> doom or that
>> doom or that.
>> They're much more pragmatic about it.
They see AI as a technology that's going
to advance their economy, advance their
society and they don't have these these
groups who are basically saying it's
going to end civilization
>> and we're making it up. The part that is
frustrating is if it was true if it was
true then we ought to talk about it and
go do something about it, right? Even
even if it's true, we ought to spend
more time doing something about it than
worrying a bunch of people who can't do
anything about it. It's our job to build
it, right?
>> Has there ever been a point in history
where so many people have so vehemently
said something that is so untrue?
>> And they're measurably they're they're
actually demonstrably untrue and it
actually makes sense as untrue. It's not
based on science. It's not based on
research. Everything that's based on
science and research proves otherwise.
Is it a fear of the frontier? Humans
have never been there. We've never seen
it. Therefore, we're scared of it and
therefore it's easy to tell everyone to
be scared of it.
>> It could be life experience as well,
David. Um, so let me give you an
example. When I first graduated from
school, I was an engineer and I didn't
do that much typing. And the reason for
for that is because I was the first
generation before software software
became popular. We had to go build the
computers to make software pop possible.
Could you imagine
in this generation every single engineer
who came into the world of engineering
you spend all your time typing
literally that's what you do when you
get a job they give you a laptop they
give you a chair and you start typing
you you type all day long you type from
the moment you wake up to the m well
there was engineering before typing
>> right
>> and so so can you imagine that the world
has a mountain of engineering work to do
where most of it is not typing anymore
Sure,
we were we had busy engineers before
typing. I think we're going to do a lot
of great engineering after typing.
>> Yeah.
>> When I say typing, I mean coding. I
mean, and so even at NVIDIA when
software engineers talk to me, I I tell
them, you're just typing. I've been
saying that forever, but obviously for
fun. And I I tell them, my favorite key
is backspace.
And and the reason for that is because
the best software is the smallest
software. Yeah. So I I want you to use
backspace software.
>> Let's actually talk about Nvidia. I
let's let's do a little tear down of
Nvidia. So uh tear down meaning just
explain the pieces because there's a lot
of strategy at play. Let's start at the
absolute bottom. So
>> Oh no,
>> this is not planned, but we know who it
is.
>> Oh no.
No.
Mr. President.
Oh, yes, sir. Um, I gotta tell you
something. It I I uh if it wasn't
because of you calling, I would I'm on
stage with the besties. I'm on stage
with the besties. [laughter]
I'm on stage with the besties. I'm on
stage with Sachs. And
>> yeah,
>> you know, the whole group.
Yeah. Jason's here. Chamat's here. David
and David is here. Yeah. I'm sitting in
front of a few thousand people
and we're talking as it turned out we
were we were talking about you.
[laughter]
Good job, sir. Good job. The fact that
you saw through all of that, I mean,
there's a lot of complexity and the fact
of the matter is you saw through all of
that and and I you know, we're all just
really grateful.
>> Tell them I said hi.
[laughter]
>> Do you want to say hi to the crowd?
Jason would like Jason would like to put
you on the
>> even Jason
speaker mode.
>> How do we put How do we put on pus
>> on? Put him on speaker.
>> Speaker. Yeah.
>> Right into the microphone.
>> Here we're going to get a mic.
>> Hang on a second.
>> Hold on, sir. We're getting a
microphone.
>> Mr. President,
>> you're you're now talking to the planet.
>> You see, the great thing about life is
that Jensen can develop the most complex
computer chip in the world that nobody
can copy for 10 years. But he can't
figure out how to put me on SPEAKER
[laughter]
THING. We have to remember this one. So
interesting the AI. It's almost as
conspiracy
and the happiest group is China and
China is very happy. And I could even
say in the country a lot of states are
happy that weren't going to get anything
because they're being uh inundated by
people that want to be there. But now
all of a sudden you see they're building
in Finland. They want to build one.
Google wants to build a big one in
Finland, which I'm not happy about
because they were unable to get
permitting. And I'm telling you, it's
all a hoax. The data centers are great
and they make people wealthy and they
make states wealthy and it's the oil of
the next 20 25 years. It's bigger than
the internet and the AI, you know, much
more so. And uh they're just playing
right into the hands of a lot of people
that don't want to see it happen. And
that could be political people. It could
also be China. And we're not going to
let that happen. It's a It's a hoax. And
>> you're right. We're not going to let
that happen, sir.
>> No, we're not going to let it happen.
The uh the robots are not going to be
taking over the world. And that's not
going to happen. You know, my uncle was
a the top probably maybe the best of all
time, frankly.
professors at MIT for 41 42 years and
can known as being one of the most
brilliant men and he was he was there
for 41 years as the top he was like at
the top top of the ladder top of did
many things Jensen knows all about it
but did many things so I have a little
genetic uh a little genetic strength if
you believe in the resource [laughter]
theory but I do I have genetic
>> that explains why you know so much about
AI I Yeah.
>> Well, I know about AI. I know I also
have common sense about AI. Uh the
robots will not be taking over. Uh the
AI will not be taking over the rest of
the world. The whole thing is a hoax.
Now, with that, we have to be a little
bit careful. We have to very be, you
know, we have to do things and we have
to do them prudently. But that doesn't
mean we're going to stop industry
because, you know, as we work on the
next 10 years about how to destroy it.
So, I'm with you all the way. I didn't
even know how you felt about it. And I
assumed you felt the same way as me.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And we if we're going to lead and I have
an expression, it's whoever wins AI
wins. That's how big it is. It's bigger
than the internet. And whoever wins AI
wins. And we can't let this kind of
stuff happen. And that includes very
much includes data centers. There are
communities that were dying that have
data centers right now. And now they're
wealthy communities. Really wealthy
communities. We're We're going to make
sure that We're going to make sure that
everybody We're going to make sure that
everybody wins in the AI race in
America. Every industry, every company,
every state, every people.
>> Good. Well, I feel strongly about it and
I have the position that can do
something about it. We're not going to
let that stuff happen. So, I have no
idea who's at the meeting. I have no
idea who the hell I'm talking to, but
I'll see. [laughter]
>> Did you Did you hear that? Did you hear
that? Thousands of people are clapping
for you, sir. All I know if you're there
[applause]
to listen to Jensen, but uh he's done an
amazing job and David has done an
amazing job and good luck to everybody
and uh we're going to stay with the
future. The country has never done
better. We have 20 trillion dollars of
investment coming into the country and
that's as opposed to much less than 1
trillion under sleepy Joe Biden and that
was [laughter] for four years. This is
in one year. So, you know, it's it's
really the country is there's ne the
country has never seen anything like it
and we're going to keep it going. And
so, thank you all very much.
>> Thank you, Mr. President.
>> Mr. President,
>> thank you.
>> I'll call you back later. Thank you, Mr.
President. Thank you.
>> Um I was unique.
>> I thought it was a bit. Did you
[laughter] know that was happening?
>> I thought it was a bit. Yeah, that was
>> it was No, it was real. I thought it was
a bit at first when I was like, put him
on speakerphone. [laughter]
Wow.
and he [clears throat] calls you. How do
you how do you think he calls you any
hour of the night, right?
>> Well, we we were we were in the uh we
were in the oval that time when he
called you
sleeping.
>> You were asleep and he like said, "Wake
him up."
>> I felt I felt so bad because he's like,
"Who's coming to this dinner?" And we go
through the list. He's like, "Well, what
about Jensen?" I said, "No, sir. We I
He's on vacation." Cuz he he had to
postpone this vacation for 5 years.
>> And he's like, "Get him on the phone."
[laughter]
>> What's vacation?
>> But what why do you think he sees
through the hoax? It's it's this is the
thing quite an extraordinary thing.
>> It was it's polling minus 80.
>> So for anyone else that's sitting in the
Oval Office. You're going to do what's
popular. You're representing the people.
This is what everyone wants. They want
to shut down the data centers and AI. It
seems to be the popular thing in the
moment. But he says it's a hoax and he
calls it. How does he do that?
>> I got to tell you, I'm not sure. And the
reason for that is because a lot of
people are falling for it. And so the
fact of the matter is it's complicated.
You know, at first, I mean, if you look
at the story, if you look at the
stories, it's all anchored on two
things. The first thing that it was
anchored on was national security. And
recently, that was all blown blown to
bits, right?
>> And so, no, that story is no longer
anchored on national security. Now, it's
anchored on safety. Now, if you want AI
to be safe, um the first thing is we
need to make sure that the the labs that
are building it are in control, that
they're they're good tests for them. uh
if we would like to have third parties
uh uh to to um uh make sure that a third
party evaluator third party evaluators
are available that's no different than
financial control. You guys know we have
auditors
>> and the auditors are quite quite um they
don't have to be as expert as we are in
our business but they just have to ask
the right questions and um I I think I
heard somebody say that it's good to
have uh independent auditors or
evaluators but they just have to have
multiple. I agree with that too. Just as
there's multiple evaluated and auditors,
it makes sure that one company doesn't
become, you know, pilled or somehow
influenced um for for whatever reason.
And so you, you know, there's a lot of
different ways that you could solve
this. Um and so I think the number one
thing is let's build the technology
safely. Let's make sure that the testing
of it is safe. And I I recognize
completely that that what what is being
built is extraordinary. Um but these are
extraordinary companies and and we ought
to hold them to to extraordinary
standards. Um and they want to be and
they want to be
>> I wanted to go back to open source for a
second. [clears throat]
Um a year ago we weren't taking it very
seriously. It was two years 18 months
behind.
>> The one thing that you know one of the
as you guys know one of the challenges
when you're on the call with President
Trump is hard to say something. Um
[laughter]
I'm going to get in trouble for that.
I'm sure he's going to call me up up on
that. But anyhow, uh what I was going to
tell him and and and all of you is that
AI is creating an enormous number of
jobs. The the the thing that he wanted
more than anything at the beginning of
the the administration and that my first
phone call with him, my first time I met
him is that he wants to create jobs in
America. He wants to re-industrialize
the United States. He wants to make sure
that United States has the energy to
support the next industrial revolution.
Without energy, there's no industrial
growth. And so he wants to make sure
that there's energy growth, that there's
job growth, that they're
re-industrializing
the supply chain. Look at everything
that we're doing right now. All of it is
happening right now as we speak. We're
creating more jobs than ever. We're
creating software jobs. We were just
talking about earlier. $400 billion
dollar of venture financing went into
the AI industry just recently. Yeah. 6
months. Well, that's created a ton of
jobs. That's created a ton of jobs. Um
it's created you know obviously enormous
amount of demand for compute which we're
I'm happy about. Um which is also which
is also creating a lot of demand for
data centers and we ought to talk about
that. I think I was just I was talking
to um uh Governor Abbott uh uh of uh
Texas and he was he was uh he wants to
appeal to the industry to make sure that
we are we are empathetic to the small
communities as we're building data
centers all of all across America just
to be better listeners. Let's actually
talk about that for a second.
[clears throat] That's
>> what's incredible about Nvidia if you if
you break down the component parts is
you've effectively had to become the
bank of AI to get the ecosystem going
and you've had to do it at all the
levels. You know, you just did this
thing with Cloverleaf where you're doing
land powers shell. You did this great
thing with Black Rockck and Goldman and
all these folks to to essentially create
the financing capability. walk us
through your capital allocation strategy
like what has to happen to get a broader
ecosystem folks to be able to come in
and underwrite this next phase.
>> Well, we're we're creating as you guys
know this is a new industrial revolution
and and um every aspect of it is true.
Um this new industry
requires manufacturing just as just as
uh the the the um electricity, internet
and now AI. We power anything, we can
find anything. Now with AI, we can ask
and know anything. Isn't that right? And
so that's our future. We tap into the
ether and we can ask it of anything we
want and it could explain it to us. Now,
in order for that to happen, it's got to
produce the intelligence. And so that's
a production process which is the reason
why this infrastructure has to get
built. But once you get the
infrastructure built, the question is um
what about all of the other layers
across the United States? Uh this
industry isn't just about the model.
It's not just about the chips. It's
mostly about the applications on top.
It's mostly about the infrastructure
layer, the data centers and all the
infrastructure, the the the the
construction, the electricity, the power
generation that all of that is involved.
And so I look across the entire
ecosystem and look for bottlenecks and
if there are places where extraordinary
companies are being built
>> constraints
>> constraints extraordinary companies
being built uh maybe it's uh uh uh
supply chain that has to uh get scaled
up so that when we're ready to deploy
compute that they'll be ready for us
land power shell and so this is no
different than looking at the supply
chain upstream. You know, I I probably
uh think about the long-term supply
chain more than most because our
company's really large and and um in
order for us to succeed, a whole bunch
of companies has to support me. You
know, it's got to uh Corning has to, you
know, Wendle at at Corning has to
support me, Lumenum, and you know, TSMC
of course and memory companies and and
so we started working with all of these
companies long before the revolution
that the the growth came so that the
growth could happen. Now I'm got now I'm
doing a downstream.
>> The compet cycle tends to be though that
the earnings over time over long
stretches of time tends to move up the
stack right towards the application
layer where you can over earn for larger
periods of time. Um I mean you bought
hugging face now you're sort of in the
actively in the serving business. I mean
it seems pretty natural that products
like open router make a lot of sense. It
seems pretty obvious that you know there
are better versions of ways to build
things like bedrock. I'm sure you think
about it. What's the natural conclusion?
Because it seems like the folks up here
have no issue trying to move down.
>> Mhm.
>> And you have the best balance sheet,
these incredible engineers, and you have
the proven experience to make it right
and engineer the product and get it out.
So, how do you think about looking up
and saying, "I could probably do that."
>> The the reason why Nvidia runs every
single model in the world, we were the
only It's incredible. Last year about a
year and a half ago the only thing we
ran was open AI.
>> Yeah.
>> And now look at amazing models are
available. The Metamuse is available.
You got gro is available. Grockbots's
incredible. Um we now run Gemini. Uh and
anthropic is is uh scaling up on our
platform as well. Uh since a year and a
half ago, you got all these frontier AI
models that are now open that are
available. So the number of models that
are are are growing. Um there's a whole
bunch of companies that I won't mention
that are building uh frontier models as
well. And the the number of AI labs are
growing. Yeah. The the ineffables, the
uh the reflections, the right the list
goes on. The physical intelligence, the
list goes on. Okay. And so all of these
labs are building on NVIDIA. And the
reason for that is because as a company,
I rather for us to help everybody
succeed instead of taking a slice out.
And so we would go up as far as we need
to but as low as possible.
>> Our strategy is go up as far as we need
to and as low as possible. And the
reason for that is because if I do that,
if I solved the if if not for Nvidia
creating QDNN, all of the frameworks
wouldn't exist. If not for us creating
Megatron uh megatron core, uh then all
of the large scale training wouldn't
have happened.
>> Wouldn't exist. Um, so we we go and we
invent all the technology necessary as
far as we need to and then we let a
thousand flowers bloom.
>> And so that posture allows us to be
quite frankly the only
>> Well, look, let's be honest that I I
agree with you. The push back would be
that it really would be great to have
more competition at the hyperscare
layer. And I think you've done a great
job supporting the NeoClouds. There are
some. And by the way, I think you
introduced me to NBS. Superb, great,
everything. They're amazing. But we need
like 50 of these guys. We need a hundred
of them. We need a thousand of them. And
it just may take some
>> Yeah. You know, it's just I'm
surprisingly uncompetitive
>> really. Yeah. [laughter] That's not my
thing. You know, my thing is kind of
like for example, I'd be more than happy
with five hyperscalers. However, um the
reason I noticed the early customers of
all the Neoclouds, all the what we call
NCPs, all the early customers were the
hyperscalers.
>> Exactly.
>> And the reason for that is because the
hyperscalers plan once a year, but the
market dynamics is so volatile right now
>> that they're always almost wrong. And so
with all these regional clouds who are
agile and they can move fast, um they
know their state or they know their
country, they know their region, they're
securing land, power and shell in a way
that's hard for somebody who sits in
Seattle or sits in Palo Alto to be able
to see the planet.
>> And so we now have basically a largecale
distributed network of companies that
are building securing land power shell
for us. and [snorts] um uh and and now
countries realize it's strategic.
>> Yeah.
>> So many countries are saying I'm going
to take my power and only give it to my
own companies,
>> right?
>> Well, Nvidia is in that country as well
and we could help the Neoclouds in that
country grow and and so whether it's
whether it's Fermas and Australia, we
just did a whole bunch of stuff in
Australia. Um brought on two more
gigabytes. Uh Southeast Asia of course
IOH and others bring on a few gigabytes.
And so we're building gigawatts. So,
we're building, you know, we're we're
scaling up. You know, it's
>> pretty clear, though. I just want to get
this one thing in. It's pretty clear
that you're going pretty high up and
getting very focused on open-source.
Obviously, you have your Neotrons doing
exceptionally well. I use them often.
Hugging face poolside and Laguna uh very
very solid product that you're now uh
aqua hiring, hiring, whatever it is. Um
and then you have your open source stack
for self-driving also uh very
disruptive. So
>> we are the frontier model in five
domains.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And so
>> you don't seem to build products to get
the silver medal. You seem to go for the
gold. So are you going for the gold? And
will you have the best hands-down
open-source model? And then
part B to that is can open source catch
up to frontier models and are you the
person to do it? So the logic the logic
Jason is that that um we will build it
because one uh we can we have the skills
to do it and because our customers need
us to do it
>> right. So, for example, Alpamo is the
world's first thinking self-driving car.
And by by thinking, by reasoning, you
don't need as much data as, you know,
you don't have to train on a few billion
hours of road data because you could
reason about it. Break down the problem
into I've seen this before. It's not
exactly the same, but it's largely the
same as that. Okay? And so, so Alpamo,
why is it necessary? Well, there's a
whole bunch of car companies. Every car
in the world is going to be autonomous,
but beyond that, every ag tech, every
truck, every van, and most of them
aren't big enough in scale to be able to
build that whole stack. So, I'll build
an extraordinary stack for them. They do
last mile adapting for their
application. Now, everything that moves
in the future could be autonomous. If
not for us building uh some of the some
of the biology models, the world
wouldn't have it. uh the the ESM2 uh
protein found language model we created
that ESM fold open fold alpha fold 2 um
all the stuff with with coup equavariant
um all of that stuff technology wouldn't
have existed if we didn't build it uh uh
one of my favorites uh proteina complexa
uh is you know synthesizing next
generation proteins and it's binding
it's groundbreaking stuff we built that
and so we'll build that because Lily
needs it and and uh you know Merc needs
it and others need it and they don't
have the capab ability to do it or they
they're not yet there and so we can make
a real contribution. So I do everything
out of need. I'm not trying to disrupt I
mean we don't wake up in the morning try
to disrupt anybody.
>> We just wake up in the morning try to
help everybody.
>> Jensen, what about what about
competitive threats that might be
emerging to your core business? Can you
just comment?
>> Just so nice.
>> Yes. Well, I know this is Well, I I
actually want I want to just get your
let's just call it a take. What's your
take on Terraab 100 million square foot
facility Elon's announced and um
>> if anybody could do it he can and the
two of us were on a flight together to a
country and um
>> with a person who sometimes calls you on
the phone. It was it was a nice plane
and and and we had like you know and you
know Elon likes to talk about these
things and and so uh we spent a lot of
time talking about it.
>> I I is that anybody could do it because
I mean you could you design chips you
don't fab them. Could your chips be fab
there or is it
>> Well, we know we we know a lot about
process technology because we're pushing
the limits of everything,
>> right? And you [clears throat] know
because we scale at such large scale uh
we have incredible memory technology
inside the company. We're the world's
best sis company. You know we got lots
of amazing.
>> So your take is you've talked a lot
about it.
>> So we could just yeah we could talk
about it and and um you can't discourage
Elon from doing it which is one of his
incred that's his superpower and once he
decides to go do something it's hard to
stop him. And so I
>> And can can you give us your take on
where China is with advanced lithography
systems? Um native grown.
>> They're going to get there by 2030.
>> By 2030. [clears throat]
>> Yeah. And 2030 is just around the
corner.
>> Yeah.
>> Also, that's how long will all be dead
at that time. So,
>> and does and for China, does that mean
the switch is flipped and then that's
all going to go into um mainland fabs
>> almost immediately?
>> You know, the the way to think about
China is really good at high volume
production.
And this is just matter of time.
>> Yeah.
>> And I you know I I think in I I think in
decades as well you know I've been
around a long time and you know for
Nvidia I've got to think about what
happens next decade and decade after
that. So two or three years is it's just
a click. It's nothing.
>> And so as far as they're concerned
they're already there.
>> They're already there.
>> Yeah.
>> Jensen Elon uh and Gwen
>> we've got to run America. We got to run.
>> Yeah. speedun.
>> So, we got
>> speedun.
>> Slowing down is definitely the wrong
strategy.
>> Well, I mean it [clears throat] it feels
apparent, I think, to most of us in the
industry that we're kind of in the AGI
moment. And it's a definition obviously
just as smart as any other human.
>> I think we're already there.
>> We're there, right? And so then super
intelligence is the next way point based
on what you see, based on your customer
base, based on your history here.
>> But Jason, I think we're there, too.
>> You think we're at super intelligence?
>> Yeah. Yeah. When you when you when you
take a narrow segment
a narrow segment I mean my my
self-driving car I don't want you to
make me an omelette I just want you to
drive the car
>> right
>> that is super intelligent
>> super it's better it's better than a
human
>> yeah yeah
>> onetenth the the accident rate
>> exactly
>> uh synthesizing proteins you know uh
doing virtual screening of proteins
we're already there
>> are you having fun being on the frontier
of humanity
>> I like Yeah, [laughter]
>> ladies and gentlemen.
>> Ladies and gentlemen,
>> I like it. I like it. And guys, guys,
it's it's it's great there. The future
is great and we want to get there.
Listen, ride the bike. A lot of us don't
have to work. But I got to tell you,
it's too good not to be.
>> So fun,
>> right? And so, so I want every we I want
to be there. I want all of you guys
there with me. We're all going to be
there. we're going to be enormously
successful together as a humanity. And
um and in the meantime, uh we got to
encourage them, urge them on. They're
doing really, really important work as
you guys know. And I want them to
succeed. Um I also would love for us to
tone down the the the the drama and most
importantly, we need all of America to
come with us. That's how we make it.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, Jensen Long.
[applause]
[music]
>> Thanks, man. Appreciate you. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> That was awesome. [music]
Only your part.
>> That was awesome. That was great.
>> Thanks, guys.
That was great, huh? Great time.